Hello everyone and
welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco. My
name is Catherine and if
you've been listening
to our recent lessons,
you know that we've been
talking a lot about food.
That's right and today we have
another lesson all about
food from a different country.
Last time we took a look at Mexican
food, Chinese food now, we are talking
about Indian food.
Okay Indian food is very
famous for being spicy
but not all of it is spicy.
Let's take a listen to today's dialogue
and find out just what kinds of food you
will find at an Indian restaurant. So where
is this mystery restaurant that we're going
to? It's an Indian restaurant. I know you
have never had Indian food so I thought you
might want to try it. That sounds great!
I am craving some type of beef dish.
Well, Indian cuisine actually doesn't serve
beef. You see cows are a sacred animal.
A very important element in the
Hindu religion so beef is not eaten. I see.
So what are we having?
Chicken? There are many amazing
dishes to choose from.
We can have some chicken
tikka masala which is an amazing curry.
It's a bit spicy but I think you can handle
it. Sounds good. I've
always heard that Indian
spices give a rich
flavor to food. Yeah.
Also we can have some naan bread which has
baked in a tandoori oven. Since you don't
use any utensils to eat you can use
this bread to scoop up the curry or rice.
What about veggies? Oh they
have a good variety of vegetable
based dishes like
Palak Panir, vegetable
samosas or dal. It all sounds so exquisite.
I can't wait. Alright we're back.
So now let's take a look at a couple of
words and phrases here on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So in
this first language takeaway
today we have words
that are about the kinds
of food we're eating
today. So the first one
the character said I am
craving some type of beef.
So to crave something.
Okay so that is a verb to crave and
that means that you have a desire.
You really want to eat something
to have a particular thing.
That's right but it's particular.
So it's something specific.
For example pregnant women are famous
for craving strange foods like pickles.
Yeah exactly. So if you
say I'm craving some ice
cream you specifically
want ice cream or maybe
vanilla ice cream.
Exactly. And this person
wants beef but unfortunately there's no
beef at Indian restaurants because cows are
what? Cows are a
sacred animal so they are
sacred in India. Sacred
means special or somehow
important in a religious way. For example
because they this is a very sacred place so
please don't use cameras or
phones and take your shoes off.
That's right so the word sacred
refers to something that is religious and
very important
for that religion.
Specifically in this occasion we're
talking about the Hindu religion.
Okay so the Hindu
religion or Hindu
ism, Hindu ism is a religion
that's widely practiced
in the world and maybe
most commonly found in India.
So you'll see a lot of
Hindu temples in India
and people don't eat
beef like we said because
cows are sacred in
the Hindu religion.
That's right. Okay so
now in India or for Indian
food it's common to not
use any type of utensil to eat.
Okay so you might be
wondering what is a utensil.
I know forks. I know spoons. Well
utensil is the word that describes all
forks, spoons and knives,
things that you eat with.
Okay so utensils are
tools for eating and
it's a very general
category. Right exactly.
So utensils are spoons,
forks, knives, everything.
Chopsticks are utensils
even. Okay very good
and now since we don't
use any utensils you
usually eat with your
hand and you scoop up
the food, the rice or
the curry. Okay to scoop
up this is a verb and usually you use your
hands to scoop something. So in this case
I can use a piece of
bread to scoop up or to
pick up some food. That's
right so the verb to scoop up.
It usually means that you somehow
make a little bowl or little figure with
your hand so that the
liquid or the food will
fit inside kind of like a
little scoop or a lot of cup.
That's right. So to scoop up, scoop
something up. All right so now let's go
back let's review this dialogue and when we
come back we're going to take a look at the
specific Indian dishes
found in this dialogue.
So where is this mystery
restaurant that we're going to?
It's an Indian restaurant. I know
you have never had Indian food so I
thought you
might want to try it.
That sounds great. I am
craving some type of beef dish.
Well, Indian cuisine actually doesn't serve
beef. You see cows are a sacred animal,
a very important element in the
Hindu religion so beef is not eaten. I see.
So what are we having?
Chicken. There are many amazing
dishes to choose from.
We can have some chicken
tikka masala which is an amazing curry.
It's a bit spicy but I think you can handle
it. Sounds good. I've
always heard that Indian
spices give a rich
flavor to food. Yeah.
Also we can have some
non bread which has
baked in a tenduri
oven. Since you don't use
any utensils to eat, you
can use this bread to
scoop up the curry or
rice. What about veggies?
Oh, they have a good
variety of vegetable based
dishes like Palak Panir,
vegetable samosas or dal.
It all sounds so
exquisite. I can't wait.
Alright, we're back
so now let's take a look
at those dishes on
language takeaway part too.
Oh, Marco, these lessons
are making me so hungry.
We've been doing them for a couple
weeks now and this one is no exception.
We talked a little bit
today about chicken dishes
and vegetable dishes but a very general
kind of dish in Indian food is a curry.
That's right. A curry.
Now, this is a noun and it's
a dish that has a
variety of spices in it.
That's right. So there
are many different
flavors, not just one
flavor. You can have chicken
curries and vegetable curries
and mutton or lamb curries.
But the thing that you need to
remember in Indian food is that there's
usually different colors
of curry, red, yellow
or green curries.
That's right. Exactly.
So the dishes are usually
called curries and an
example of a curry. We have a chicken tikka
masala curry. Okay, so we know that there's
chicken in it and tikka
means that it's grilled
chicken and masala is the
name of the spice or the curry.
The spice that's in that curry.
Exactly. Exactly. So
a curry is kind of like
a thick sauce with
pieces of chicken in it.
In this case for the
chicken tikka masala, it's
a little bit spicy
and it's a color red.
All right. So we've got
the chicken tikka masala
masala and usually you eat this with rice
or bread. But in India, there's a special
there are many
different kinds of bread.
But the special bread we heard
today was called non bread.
Right, non bread. And it's just basically
a type of bread. Now it's not like
the bread that you
usually have at home.
It's a flat bread. So it kind of
looks like a pancake almost.
It does. It's not
fluffy. It's flat.
And the way they cook
it is they use this special
oven and they cook
it inside the oven.
Now the question is what
is that oven called Marco?
That's right. The oven that
we heard is a tandoori oven.
Okay. So tandoori is
just the name of this oven.
It's also a style of
cooking in India.
And it's actually
one of my favorite
kinds of Indian food because you have these
many different kinds of grilled meats.
You can have tandoori
chicken, tandoori, mutton,
things like that. Exactly.
So a tandoori oven
is a type of oven
usually made from clay.
That's why it's called tandoori.
Now towards the end, we also
have some vegetarian options
because as we heard in
India, they don't eat beef.
And many people
are also vegetarians.
They don't need any
type of meat at all. So the
first vegetable base dish that we heard is
a palak paneer. That's interesting actually
because paneer is is curd
or like a cheese type of thing.
So it's it's usually white and
comes in rectangles. Yeah. And and paneer,
you can have many different flavors of it.
But paneer generally is a kind of a
cheese like a cottage cheese. That's right.
And palak is actually
spinach. So it's a dish that it
kind of looks like a
thick sauce, green sauce,
which is made out of
spinach. And within it,
it has little pieces of
this type of cheese.
So I love this dish.
It's very, very delicious.
We also have vegetable
samosas. Now a samosa.
What's that? This
is a great dish.
This is often used as an
appetizer or as a snack.
You see these on carts
or on the street in India.
Now samosas are like
pyramids or triangles.
And inside they have
vegetables. Okay.
So you can have
potatoes and peas or lentil.
No, not lentils. You can
have potatoes and peas.
And they're a little bit
crunchy on the outside
and soft on the inside.
They're very tasty.
I guess the equivalent
would be to it's something
like an egg roll more
like a dumpling or like
a dumpling because
it is deep fried. That's
deep fried. And
we also have a dal.
So this is actually a type
of lentil as you mentioned.
That's right. So dal is a lentil dish.
And it can be flavored in different ways.
But basically lentils
are is very, very, very,
very small round things.
They're very good for your health.
And dal is a kind of
a soupy lentil dish.
That's right. So
lentil is the category
of this type of, I don't know if it's
not a grain. It's a legume. It's a legume
exactly. So it may
sound a little bit weird.
But we'll put some
pictures of different types
of lentils because it's
like saying potatoes.
There are many different
types of potatoes.
Sweet potato and all
this. And the same thing
goes with lentil. So we'll put some
pictures so you can see what it looks like.
But now when we go back,
let's listen to the dialogue
again. Let's review everything
and we'll be right back.
So where is this mystery restaurant that
we're going to? It's an Indian restaurant.
I know you have
never had Indian food.
So I thought you
might want to try it.
That sounds great. I am
craving some type of beef dish.
Well, Indian cuisine
actually doesn't serve beef.
You see cows are a sacred animal, a very
important element in the Hindu religion.
So beef is not eaten. I see.
So what are we having
chicken? There are many amazing
dishes to choose from.
We can have some chicken
tikka masala, which
is an amazing curry.
It's a bit spicy, but I
think you can handle
it. Sounds good. I've
always heard that Indian
spices give a rich
flavor to food. Yeah.
Also we can have some
non bread, which has
baked in a tenduri
oven. Since you don't use
any utensils to eat, you
can use this bread to
scoop up the curry or
rice. What about veggies?
Oh, they have a good
variety of vegetable-based
dishes like palakpanir,
vegetable samosas, or dal.
It all sounds so
exquisite. I can't wait.
Alright, we're back.
So Indian food has a
reputation of being spicy,
but it's very, very delicious.
That's right. And you know what people
always tell me, at least my Indian friends
always tell me, is that
Indian food, Indian
food is like saying Chinese
food. We have some
general idea, but every different
part of India has its own special foods.
That's right. And so what we get in America
at Indian restaurants might not be the same
as what we get at
Indian restaurants in India.
So I just want to say
that. But generally,
you can find these dishes at
any Indian restaurants in America.
That's right. Actually, if next time you're
in an Indian restaurant, or if you ever
go ask them from
what region or what area
of India the food is
from, because it may be
northern Indian cuisine. And obviously that
is going to be a little bit different than
maybe the southern. I think the
southern is supposed to be spicy.
Exactly. And it's just
like in every country,
even in our own home
countries, maybe the
food from the coast or from the north will
be different from the south or the inland.
And I just want to make
one more comment.
One of my favorite things
to do that many Indian
restaurants offer in
America is the lunch buffet.
So a buffet is
basically a self-serve of
food. So the restaurant
will put out many
different dishes. And
you can take as much as
you want of each, but you pay one price.
All right. So it's $11.99 or something.
That's very, very good. And yeah, so I
often do this when I'm home in the states.
And I just, you know, I get to pick my
favorite dishes and I eat as much as I want.
And actually, I think
one other thing that's
worth mentioning, we
didn't mention in the
dialogue, but Indian
sweets and the tea is
very, very good. The
milk tea that they drink
in India is delicious.
And the sweets are very, very good.
That's right. They're famous for being
very good and not very healthy for you.
Yeah, exactly. They're very sweet.
If you're in a resident Indian restaurant,
take note, look for these different things.
And let us know. Do you like to eat Indian
food if so? What's your favorite dish?
All right. So we'll see
you guys at our website,
www.EnglishPot.com.
And until next time, bye.